xe.net 2017-12-31

# XE - Privacy Policy

Effective as of May 30, 2017 (the "Effective Date"). 

## Introduction

We reserve the right to modify this Policy at any time, and we will notify you of any material changes to the Policy by posting the modified Policy at <http://xe.com/privacy.php> and changing the Effective Date at the top. We encourage you to check this page periodically for any changes. This Policy is incorporated into, and subject to, XE's Terms of Use at <http://xe.com/legal/>. By using or navigating XE's web site located at <http://xe.com/> or any product or service offered by XE (collectively, the "Services"), you acknowledge that you have read, understand, and agree to be bound by this Policy or any modified Policy as posted. If you do not agree to these terms, please do not use or access the Services. 

## What information is collected?

We do not collect personally identifiable information except where you specifically provide us with such information. With your consent, we may collect your full name, e-mail address, street address, telephone number, and other contact information. We may also collect credit card information from you. We generally collect this personal information on our registration and order forms when you sign up to receive products or services through our Services.

Aggregate technical information (such as IP addresses, screen resolution, browser language, etc.) and anonymous demographic information (such as your postal or zip code, the web site that you came from, etc.) is collected during your usage of the Services.

## What is done with the information collected?

We use personal information and other demographic or profile information you provide to us to fulfill your orders or requests, to attempt to prevent fraudulent transactions, to improve the content of our web page in order to enhance your experience, to contact you when necessary and, if you have consented and you have not withdrawn your consent, to contact you with marketing communications in relation to our Services (see Direct marketing by XE and Our Group below).

Whenever possible, we use non-identifiable information (such as IP addresses and anonymous demographic information) rather than personal information. Non-identifiable information is used to tailor your experiences with our Services by showing content in which we think you will be interested and displaying content according to your preferences. We may use aggregate data for a variety of purposes, including analyzing user behavior and characteristics in order to measure interest in (and use of) the various portions and areas of our Services. We also use the information collected to evaluate and improve our services and analyze traffic to our Services.

Personal information collected on our Services is typically stored and processed in Canada; however, in some instances, it may be transferred, stored, and/or processed outside of Canada. It is important for you to note that the laws on holding data in Canada (or any other country in which we transfer, store or process your data) may be less stringent than the laws of your country, but XE intends to adhere to the principles set forth in this Policy, unless otherwise required by applicable laws. By using our Services, you consent to the transfer of your personal information to any country in the world in accordance with the terms of this Policy.

## Is information collected shared with third parties?

XE may share your information with our agents, processors, or contractors in order to fulfil your purchase order. We may also transfer information to affiliate companies in the Euronet Worldwide Inc. group (of which we are part) including HiFX Europe Limited and companies operating under the “HiFX” brand ( **“HiFX”** ) and Euronet Payment Services Limited and companies operating under the “Ria” brand ( **“Ria”** ) (see: www.euronetworldwide.com) ( **“Our Group”** ). If you have consented and you have not withdrawn your consent, affiliate companies in Our Group may contact you directly with marketing communications in relation to the Services or their respective services (see Direct marketing by XE and Our Group below).

You should note that XE is opposed to third party spam mail activities and does not participate in such mailings, nor do we release or authorize the use of membership data to third parties for such purposes.

We may use statistical analysis of aggregate information to inform advertisers of aggregate user demographics and behavior, as well as the number of users that have been exposed to or clicked on their advertising banners. We will provide only aggregate data from these analyses to third parties.

We may share information we collect with third party service providers to manage certain aspects of the services we provide, such as maintaining our servers and processing or fulfilling orders for products and services you purchase through the Services. We ensure that the third party service providers that we share your information with have privacy policies in place substantially similar to our own.

Posts you make to XE Community forums are screened for spam using Mollom, whose privacy policy can be found at: <http://mollom.com/web-service-privacy-policy>

We may transfer your information to a third party as a result of a sale, acquisition, merger, or reorganization involving XE, Our Group, related companies, or any of their respective assets.

We may also disclose your information in special cases if required to do so by law, court order, or other governmental authority, or when we believe in good faith that disclosing this information is otherwise necessary or advisable, such as to identify, contact, or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to – or interfering with – the rights or property of XE, the Services, another user, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities (for example, identify theft or fraud).

## How do we advertise?

Advertisements that appear in the Services are generally delivered (or "served") directly to you by third party advertisers, and they automatically receive your IP address when this happens. These third party advertisers may also download cookies to your computer or use other technologies to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to personalize advertising content. Doing this allows them to recognize your computer each time they send you an advertisement in order to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to personalize advertising content. In this way, they may compile information about where individuals using your computer or browser saw their advertisements and determine which advertisements were clicked. Third party advertisers have no access to the information you have provided to XE unless you choose to provide it to them yourself directly.

We use a small number of industry-leading advertising services suppliers, each of whom has their own privacy policy in place covering the data they collect:

The XE.com website uses Google AdWords, including the remarketing and Similar Audiences features. This enables Google, through the use of cookies, to identify the fact that you have visited our website, to track aspects of your usage of our website, and combine that with what it knows about your usage of other websites in the Google ad network. We use these services to advertise to visitors of Google ad network websites who have previously visited our website or who Google deems to have shared interests with visitors of our website.

Of course, any data collected through your use of our site will be used in accordance with our own privacy policy and Google’s privacy policy.

You can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the [Google Ad Preferences page](http://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/), including opting out of interest-based advertising. 

## Do our Services use cookies?

Yes. "Cookies" are pieces of information (actually, alphanumeric identifiers) generated by web servers and stored in your computer for future access. Cookies cannot view or retrieve data from other cookies, nor can they capture files or data stored on your computer. We, our partners, and our suppliers use cookie technology to enhance your online experience by making it easier for you to navigate through our Services or make a feature work better. We also use cookies to track affiliates that refer you to our Services. These particular cookies are saved on your computer and collect no data from you. Generally, cookies can be disabled. The "help" portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. If you would like to use the Services, you may do so without accepting cookies. However, you should understand that if you choose not to accept cookies, some areas of the Services may not function properly or optimally and you will not be permitted to access certain secured areas of the Services.

For more information on cookies, see: <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/faqs/cookie-file.html>

## Do our Services use web beacons?

Yes. "Web beacons" (also known as "web bugs") are small images, generally a single transparent pixel, served to you as part of a web page or other document. Web beacons may be used in parts of our Services for purposes such as site traffic reporting, unique visitor counts, advertising auditing and reporting, and personalization. These beacons do not collect personally identifiable information, and do not transfer any personally identifiable information to third parties. If beacons are used by any of our advertising services suppliers, that supplier's privacy policy governs their use. Please see the section "How do we advertise" above for a list of advertisers and policies.

For more information on web beacons, see: <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/faqs/beacons.html>

## How long is information retained?

Different information is used for different purposes, and is subject to different standards and regulations. In general, information is retained for such period of time as is felt necessary to provide you with services you request, to comply with applicable regulations or legislation, and to ensure that you have a reasonable opportunity to access the information. If you no longer consent to us retaining your personal information, you can request that it be removed by contacting us as outlined at: <http://xe.com/contact.php>

## Is correspondence that you send to us saved?

Yes. If you send us correspondence, including e-mails and faxes, we may retain such information along with any records of your account. We may also retain customer service correspondence and other correspondence involving you, XE, our partners, and our suppliers. We may retain these records in order to provide you with services you request, to measure and improve our customer service, and to investigate potential fraud and violation of XE's Terms of Use. We may, over time, delete these records.

## Is information submitted in public forums confidential?

No. The Services may offer chat rooms, forums, message boards, or news groups to our users. IT IS IMPORTANT TO REMEMBER THAT ANY INFORMATION DISCLOSED IN THESE AREAS BECOMES PUBLIC INFORMATION. Accordingly, you should exercise extreme caution when deciding to disclose your personal information and you do so at your own risk.

## Is the website secure?

Yes, the portions of our website (and our other Services) that handle sensitive confidential information are secure.

We are committed to maintaining the security of your information and have measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. We employ the latest and most secure techniques available for protecting our systems from intrusion by unauthorized individuals, and we are constantly upgrading our security as better methods become available. Our data center utilizes state-of-the-art physical security measures to prevent unauthorized access to the facility. In addition, all information is stored in a secure location behind firewalls and other sophisticated security systems with limited (need-to-know) administrative access. All XE employees who have access to, or are associated with, the processing of personal information are contractually obligated to respect the confidentiality of your information and abide by the privacy standards we have established. Please be aware that no security measures are perfect or impenetrable. Therefore, although we use industry standard practices to protect your privacy, we cannot (and do not) guarantee the absolute security of personal information.

## Does this Policy apply to other websites?

No. The Services contain links to other Internet websites. By clicking on a third party advertising banner or certain other links, you will be redirected out of the Services and to such third party websites.

We may also permit third parties to offer subscription or registration-based services promoted through our own Services. In some instances, these other services may be co-branded or use XE's trademarks under license; however, others services have their own respective privacy policies. For example, "XE Money Transfer" is branded using XE's trade marks, but it is a third party service operated by our affiliate company, HiFX (not XE); consequently, "XE Money Transfer" is subject to HiFX's privacy policy, and not this Policy. 

We are not responsible for the privacy policies of other websites or services. You should make sure that you read and understand any applicable third party privacy policies, and you should direct any questions concerns to the relevant third party administrators or webmasters prior to providing any personally identifiable information.

## Direct marketing by XE and Our Group

With your consent, we and/or affiliate companies within Our Group may sometimes contact you (by email, SMS text, letter or phone) in order to provide targeted marketing about our Services or their services (as the case may be). Such marketing communications will only be sent to you if you have given your consent when you registered for our Services and have not withdrawn such consent.

All marketing e-mails you receive from us or companies in Our Group will include specific instructions on how to unsubscribe and you may unsubscribe at any time.

Additionally, you can contact us as directed at the following link to unsubscribe from marketing from us and Our Group: <http://xe.com/contact.php>

## Can personal information be updated or corrected?

Yes. You may correct or update your personal information or to otherwise request removal of your information from our database by writing to our Privacy Officer:

  * by e-mail to [privacy@xe.com](mailto:privacy@xe.com) ; or,
  * as directed at: <http://xe.com/contact.php>

We value your opinion. If you have any comments or questions about our Privacy Policy, you can e-mail or write to us at the addresses above.
